Guide to the Elithe Hamilton Kirkland Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Poetry, 1944-1988, undated
  - Mother of a Writer (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Mother Star (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - "Music will be furnished..." (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - "My thoughts that are traveling along memory's way..." (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - My Town (college assignment) (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Mysteries of Life (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Natural Gas (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Ode to Education Reporters (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Orcas Island (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Out of the Shadows (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - The Pale Blue Cow (A boarding house lament) (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Petroleum (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Picking Cotton (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Pioneer Texas Women (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Prayer for Balance and Tranquility (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Prayer for Love (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Prayer for Nature (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Prayer for a Set of Masters (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Prayer for a Star/Prayer for the People of Our Galaxy (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Problem Solved (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Quadroon Maid (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - A Revelation (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - A River Has a Soul (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Seeing the Big Bend Country for the First Time (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - She Dwells in Beauty (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - Signs of Spring (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - A Son You Have (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Sonnet to a Boarding House (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Soul Encounters (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Soul Power (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Spring - But My Poem Is Different (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - The Spring Has Brought a Glad Surprise (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - A Sweetheart's Letter on a Rainy Day (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - "Talked with friends..." (Box 17, Folder 64)
  - "Tell me not in mournful numbers..." (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - "Thanksgivin' is a time..." (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - There Was A Handsome Young Man Near Clymer (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - There Was a Valley Deep and Wide (Box 17, Folder 68)
  - Thinking of Rev. Charles B. Diltz (Box 17, Folder 69)
  - To John Bryant for Louise (Box 17, Folder 70)
  - War Poems (Box 17, Folder 71)
    An Army of Dads
    Fighting Men
    For Our Homes (aka Back Home)
    Freedom From Fear
    Freedom From Want
    The Friend
    A Girl's Picture
    Hit 'Em Again Harder!
    I Saw the Flag
    The Kid
    A Mother's Prayer
    Texans On The Alert! We Shall Not Fear
    The Wife's Letters
    Strengthen Thy Heart (Book of poems dedicated to the men who work and fight in the service of their country to defend the peace of their homes.) Poems include:
    We Shall Not Fear!
    Fighting Man's Prayer
  - "When you were born you may always hide..." (Box 17, Folder 72)
  - Where Have All The Willows Gone? (Box 17, Folder 73)
  - Whispers (Box 17, Folder 74)
  - Widow's Weeds (Box 17, Folder 75)
  - Unidentified, some possibly by EHK as a young child (Box 17, Folder 76)
  - Poetry written by Jim Beal (Box 17, Folder 77)
  - Poetry written by others, including Jenny Lind Porter's "Wedded Souls" (Box 17, Folder 78)
- Radio Scripts, 1940-1952
  Arranged in alphabetical order by the name of the series or show, these scripts date from Kirkland days at UT Austin's Radio House, circa 1940-1947. Typescripts and working drafts are included, as well as some photographs of the Radio House staff, including J. Frank Dobie. Of particular interest is the series entitled "Guardians of Freedom", which includes documents related to the Peck Woodside story Kirkland covered in Mexico.
  - Brandon Case, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Cub Scout Recording (Jim Beal) George Washington Theme (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "Dobie Day at Southwestern University", October 29, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "From This Land: Series on Folklore of the Southwest" - Program No. 1 "Kingdom of the Tejas" (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - "Guardians of Freedom" Series - Broadcast No. 6 "Tabasco...Where People Are Looking Up", March 9, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - "Guardians of Freedom" Series - Broadcast No. 7 "Chiapas...Jungle Borderland", March 16, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Peck Woodside research
    - Correspondence (including correspondence between Peck Woodside and Elithe Hamilton Beal) (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Photographs (prints and negatives) (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - General research material (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "Nazi Base in Mexican Jungle - A Part of the Peck Woodside Story: A Confidential Report, September 1941" (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "Nazi Sabotage Over Mexican Jungles" (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "Mexico's Toonerville Trolley of the Air" (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "What Has Been Done" (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - "Know Your Neighbor Series" Program No. 1, "The Spanish Southwest", July 9, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - "March of Memories" University Junior High, May 24, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - "Radio House Review" Program No. 1 - "El Salvador...Healing Hand of the Continent", May 8, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - "Reading Is Adventure", January 6, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 16a)
  - "Straight Texas: A Series of Six Broadcasts" - No. 1: Trail Thunder (March 11, 1941); No. 2: Riders of the Stars (March 18, 1941); No. 3: Mustangs and Cow Horses (March 24, 1941); No. 4: The Longhorns (April 8, 1941); No. 5: In a Stagecoach (April 15, 1941); No. 6: Buried Treasure (April 22, 1941) (one original copy and one bound photocopy), March 11, 1941- April 22, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
  - "Strange Loyalty" (30 minute radio play), 1941 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - "Sweet Land of Liberty Series on Texas Farm and Home Program" - Audition, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "Sweet Land of Liberty Series on Texas Farm and Home Program" - Program No. 1 - "Coleman County", undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - "Sweet Land of Liberty Series on Texas Farm and Home Program" - Program No. 2 - "Star Lone Star Farmer", undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - "Sweet Land of Liberty Series on Texas Farm and Home Program" - Program No. 14 - "War New Year", January 2, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - "The Taxpayer's Dream" (a Skit for B. and P. W. Dinner), undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "Texas Is Terrific" production: EHK, script: Ruth Hunnicut, circa 1943-1944 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - "Texas Quality Network...A Transcription" Special Broadcast Farm and School Parade, February 28, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "Texas Resources", undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "United War Chest of Texas", October 10, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - "'Whoopee It Yi' with J. Frank Dobie at Radio House" (drafts and correspondence), October 10, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Scripts by other Radio House staff
    - "A Yuletide Prayer", production and script by Joe Murphy, December 17, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "Mary and the Fairy" by Norman Corwin (Box 19, Folder 14a)
    - Radio House correspondence (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Radio House printed material, including Ms. Beal's Press Card and business card (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Radio House photographs (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Short Stories, 1936-1990, undated
  This subseries includes detailed documentation on the creation of Kirkland's short stories "The Disappearance of Widow Ellen", "Peck Woodside", and "Leet's Christmas". Also included are drafts of many incomplete short stories.
  - "The Disappearance of Widow Ellen", 1982
    - Correspondence including correspondence with Shearer Publishers and colleagues Tardan and Salm, 1982-1990 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Draft - Screenplay version (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Cover art ideas (photographs) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Drafts (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
    - Bound versions (Box 20, Folder 7-9)
  - "Leet's Christmas", 1985-1986
    - Copyright (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Drafts (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Financial records (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Notes (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Poems (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Published in "Hill Country Magazine" (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - White Chapel Press, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - "The One Who Laughed", 1947
    - Correspondence (including J. Frank Dobie) (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Draft (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Notes (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Incomplete
    - "Blighted College Romance" (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "Crane Guidance Plan", 1936 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "Farm Machinery "- Trade article (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Homes as Schools" (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - "Horses" (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - "I Forgot" (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - "The Imp and I" (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - "Letters, By Betty" (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - "Lone Star Feature", 1930 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - "Notes on Price of Speed and Social Insecurity" (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - "Permanent or Percolator" (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - "Summary of Texas Agriculture" (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - "Visit of Yourself" (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - "What a Young Wife Has Learned" (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Unidentified fragments and notes (Box 21, Folder 26)
- Songs, undated
  Kirkland wrote songs which appeared in her short stories and musicals, as well as many which have not appeared in any of her works. Her songs are arranged here in alphabetical order, and typically include one draft of the song only.
  - Back Alley Bonnie (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Tree Love (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Da Man On Da Mule (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Do I Look Alright? (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Each Atom Is a Melody (copyright information only) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - I Want A Space Man (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - I'm in Love Again (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Light Me Three Candles, Darling (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Long Live America (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - The Old Timer Sings (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Praise to Lindbergh (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Sugar Bowl (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Two Toned Honey From Texas (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Wake Up Bright (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - What D'Ya Think? (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified fragments (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Music for published songs not by EHK: Nat King Cole's Answer Me, My Love and Morey Amsterdam's Rum and Coca-Cola (Box 22, Folder 17)
- Television Scripts, 1953-1964
  This small subseries includes drafts of the 1953 script "Seminole Bill's Lost Mine", developed from a series Kirkland worked on with J. Frank Dobie, called "The Unfenced World".
  - Seminole Bill's Lost Mine (from series Kirkland worked on with Dobie, "The Unfenced World"), 1953 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Shakespearean Youth Fantasy, University of Texas, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 19)
- Personal Papers, 1910-1991, undated
  Material relating to Kirkland's personal life and interests are divided into several subseries: awards; biographical notes; clippings; correspondence; J. Frank Dobie material; notes; photographs; speeches; subject files; and speeches.
  Awards (1953-1987) Kirkland won many awards during her lifetime, and was inducted into the Texas Women's Hall of Fame by Gov. Bill Clements in 1987. This subseries includes correspondence, photographs, and ephemera related to these honors. Awards are listed in alphabetical order.
  Biographical Notes / Career Summaries (1910-1991, undated) Resumes and other lists of Kirkland's accomplishments, degrees and certificates, scrapbooks of favorite sayings, and small amount of legal documents related to family issues are included in this subseries. Also included is material added to Kirkland's collection by her son, James Beal, which includes information regarding Kirkland's funeral service. This material is arranged in chronological order.
  Clippings (1934-1991. undated) These general clippings pertain to Kirkland's publications and public appearances, and are arranged in chronological order. Correspondence (1920-1991, undated) Letters are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent, and relate to both personal and professional subjects. While correspondence most closely related to a specific work is filed with that work, more general material can be found here. Family correspondence, including letters between Kirkland and her parents dating back to 1924 are included, as well as letters between Kirkland and her husband, Dr. R.D. Kirkland. Fan letters, letters from friends and colleagues, and general business letters are also included here.
  J. Frank Dobie Material (1944-1976, undated) This subseries documents Kirkland's long- standing interest in and friendship with J. Frank Dobie, whom she first met while a graduate student at UT Austin. Correspondence with Mr. Dobie, clippings of articles of and by Dobie, and books by Dobie inscribed to Kirkland, comprise the bulk of this group. Also included is Kirkland's research and correspondence related to the first "Dobie Day", a celebration she helped create to honor Dobie.
  Notes (undated) Handwritten notes related to general topics and to Kirkland's dreams appear in this subseries, many on note cards filed according to Kirkland's own subject scheme. Topics include Texas history, land use, specific people.
  Photographic Material (1910-1991, undated) Items in this subseries have been arranged in chronological order by decades, and represent Kirkland's childhood through her last years. Many members of her family, favorite dogs, and close friends are represented here.
  Speeches (ca. 1940-1991, undated) Correspondence and publicity material related to speeches made by Kirkland, including drafts of several speeches, but not all. Many of these speeches were given at small town public libraries, and include photographs. This subseries also includes documents related to the literary speaking tour Kirkland participated in called "Texas Voices", a celebration of the Texas Sesquicentennial in 1986. Subjects (1936-1991, undated) These files of clippings and notes collected by Kirkland document her wide ranging interests, from Colt Revolvers to Numerology to the Texas Institute of Letters.
  Artifacs and Oversized Materials Small carved animals, horseshoes, a Texas shaped bowl and a typewriter as well as larger drafts, photographs, and signed poems make up this subseries.
  - Awards, 1953-1987
    - American Association for State and Local History Award of Merit, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Theta Sigma Phi Outstanding Authors (given at 11th Annual Writers Roundup), 1959 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - North Texas State University Distinguished Alumna, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - National Society Daughters of the American Revolution History Award Medal, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Texas Women's Hall of Fame, 1987
    - Acceptance speech, award (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Clippings (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Nomination form (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Photographs (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Programs (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Biographical Sketches / Career Summaries, 1924-1991, undated
    - "A Sketch of My Life" (written while at Denton Teacher's College), circa 1927 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Commencement scrapbook, Coleman High School, includes salutatory address given by Elithe Hamilton, 1924-1925 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Pi Kappa Delta constitution and ephemera, 1926-1928 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - North Texas State Teachers College B.A. degree and Teachers Permanent Certificate (also senior year memento book), 1928 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Professional and Educational History - Age 31, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - University of Texas, M.A. degree, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - University of Texas thesis "A Study of Pupil Mobility Affecting High School Seniors", June 1940 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Professional History (partial) - NTSTC Degree and UT correspondence re: positions help, including Radio House, 1939-1942 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - "My Views on a Subject I Consider Vital", 1983 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Chronological Career Summary, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - "Brief Sketch Professional Data: Elithe Hamilton Kirkland, Communicator", 1984 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Bio Packet - Shearer Publishing, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Family History, 1983, 1992, undated
    - Notes and pieces, photos used in White Chapel: Coleman County, Texas, by Estill Franklin Allen, Editor. Coleman, Texas: White Chapel Cemetery Association, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Book of favorite poems and sayings, pressed flowers (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Personal calendar, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Legal/Financial, 1910-1986
    - Dedication of "The Academy" (house at 400 Academy Dr. Austin. Later known as Kirkland/Mather House, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Income tax returns, 1943-1947 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, receipts, transfers, etc. regarding real estate, and regarding loans to offset medical expenses for Mr. B. F. Hamilton's final illness (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Sketches / Career Summaries ( Created and/or maintained by son, James Beal)
    - Resume and accomplishments (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Funeral information EHK (service program, obituary), 1992 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, General, 1934-1991, undated
    - 1934 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - 1952 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - 1959 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - 1961 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - 1964 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - 1967 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - 1979 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - 1984 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - 1985 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - 1986 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - 1987 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - 1988 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1991, undated
    - A, 1960-1984 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Adams, H., 1979 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - American Magazine, 1933 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Avon Books (largely re: Divine Average), 1977-1982 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - B, 1959-1990 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Beal, Jim and Roberta to E. H. Kirkland, 1986-1991 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Beal, Jim, from E. H. Kirkland, 1950-1987
      - 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - 1980-1985 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - 1973-1979 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - 1972 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - 1966-1969 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - 1960-1965 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - 1950-1959 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Bogy, Dr. Louis T. (and Mayor Henry Cisneros), 1987-1988 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Brister, Bernard, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Bryant, Presley (Fort-Worth Star Telegram), 1938-1945 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - C, 1935-1984 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Chapman, Dr. A. L. (U.S. Navy, Bureau of Naval Personnel), 1943-1945 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Clifford, J. L. (Lonnie), 1983 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Colliers/New York Times, 1934 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Copyright, 1953-1988 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - D, 1937-1985 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Day, Donald (Southwest Review), 1940-1944 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Doubleday (Evelyn Oppenheimer, EHK's literary agent), 1973-1977 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - E, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Edwards, M. J., 1972-1975 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Eves, Victoria, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Evergreens, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - F, 1936-1991 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Fan letters - special, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Faulk, John Henry (including two 1939 English papers by Faulk), 1953-1991 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Friedman, Allan, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - G, 1936-1991 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Galloway, Don, 1977-1992 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Goddard, Ruth, 1959-1991 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Commission for Women, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Gross, Henry, 1962-1969 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - H, 1937-1991 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Hall, Manly P., 1985-1988 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Hamilton, Mr. and Mrs. B. F. (from EHK), 1924-1963, undated
      - 1924 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - General, 1925 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - January-March 1925 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - April-October 1925 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - November-December 1925 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - 1926 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - "The Break Up", 1926 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - 1927 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - 1928 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - 1930 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - 1931 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - 1932 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - 1934 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - 1938 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - 1939 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - 1940 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - 1949 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - 1950 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - 1951 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - 1952 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - 1955 (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - 1956 (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - 1957 (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - 1961-1963 (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Hamilton, Mrs. B. F. (Eva) (to EHK), 1933-1961, undated
      - 1933 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - 1937 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - 1939 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - 1948 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - 1950 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - 1954 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - 1957-1959 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - 1961 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Hamilton, Marvin ("Family Data"), 1969 (Box 32, Box 1)
    - Hammock, Robert, 1935-1937 (Box 32, Box 2)
    - Heflin, Bertrand, 1941 (Box 32, Box 3)
    - Hodges, Eudora, 1986 (Box 32, Box 4)
    - Hunt, Andrew, 1986 (Box 32, Box 5)
    - Hyder, Bullock, 1932-1982 (Box 32, Box 6)
    - I-J, 1984-1985 (Box 32, Box 7)
    - Jefferson (Texas) Library, 1984-1989 (Box 32, Box 8)
    - Jorde, Jo Ellen (World Cultural Alliance), 1986 (Box 32, Box 9)
    - K, 1936-1977 (Box 32, Box 10)
    - Keenan, Pat, 1936 (Box 32, Box 11)
    - Keller, Caroline, 1989 (Box 32, Box 12)
    - Kirkland, Elithe Hamilton (to Kirkland, Dr. Roy Defoe), 1942-1971 (Box 32, Box 13-14)
    - Kirkland, Dr. Roy Defoe (to Kirkland, Elithe H.) (Box 33, Box 1-5)
    - Knopf Publishers, Inc., 1963 (Box 33, Box 6)
    - Kurtz, Dorothy (traveled with EHK to Villahermosa, Tabasco to research the "Guardians of Freedom" series for Radio House, September 1941, met Peck Woodside on this trip), 1943-1987 (Box 33, Box 7)
    - L, 1937-1973 (Box 33, Box 8)
    - Lind, Jenny, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Box 9)
    - Littauer, Kenneth, 1934-1956 (Box 33, Box 10)
    - Little, Brown & Co., 1952-1956 (Box 33, Box 11)
    - M, 1935-1990 (Box 33, Box 12)
    - May, Yvonne, 1991 (Box 33, Box 13)
    - Morrow, Anita, 1966-1967 (Box 33, Box 14)
    - Morrow, Otho, 1987 (Box 33, Box 15)
    - Murphy, Joe, 1944-1971 (Box 34, Box 1)
    - N, 1944-1990 (Box 34, Box 2)
    - Nelson, Willie, undated (Box 34, Box 3)
    - O, 1961 (Box 34, Box 4)
    - O'Daniel, Mr., undated (Box 34, Box 5)
    - Oppenheimer, Evelyn, 1978-1985 (Box 34, Box 6)
    - Orchard, Malcolm, 1952-1985 (Box 34, Box 7)
    - P, 1936-1990 (Box 34, Box 8)
    - Phillips, Naomi, 1951-1970 (Box 34, Box 9)
    - Purcell, Becky, 1948-1967 (Box 34, Box 10)
    - Purcell, Watson, 1920 (Box 34, Box 11)
    - Q-R, 1932-1991 (Box 35, Box 1)
    - Ramsey, Loyce, 1956-1982 (Box 35, Box 2)
    - Rush, Michael, 1961-1967 (Box 35, Box 3)
    - S, 1934-1986 (Box 35, Box 4)
    - Salm, Cynthia, 1989-1990 (Box 35, Box 5)
    - Schulze, Blythe, 1976-1985 (Box 35, Box 6)
    - Shaw, Sgt. Hugh, 1944-1945 (Box 35, Box 7)
    - Smith, Julia, 1936 (Box 35, Box 8)
    - Southwest Texas State Teachers College, 1953-1956 (Box 35, Box 9)
    - T, 1960-1985 (Box 36, Box 1)
    - Tarplay, Fred, 1984-1985 (Box 36, Box 2)
    - Teplitsky, Louis, 1961 (Box 36, Box 3)
    - Texas Folklore Society, 1951-1954 (Box 36, Box 4)
    - Texas Institute of Letters, 1952-1985 (Box 36, Box 5)
    - Texas Monthly, 1987-1990 (Box 36, Box 6)
    - Texas State Historical Association, 1979-1988 (Box 36, Box 7)
    - Trombley, Mike and Gladys, 1962-1972 (Box 36, Box 8)
    - U, 1940-1963 (Box 36, Box 9)
    - V, 1964-1965 (Box 36, Box 10)
    - Vogel, Willie, undated (Box 36, Box 11)
    - W, 1960-1990 (Box 36, Box 12)
    - West Texas Sun, 1989 (Box 36, Box 13)
    - Western Writers of America, 1984-1986 (Box 36, Box 14)
    - Westmoreland, Sally, 1954-1956 (Box 36, Box 15)